camerabits.com 2019-03-17

# Privacy Policy | Camera Bits, Inc.

This Privacy Policy applies to data collection and security practices of Camera Bits, Inc., an Oregon corporation (“ **Camera Bits** ”) regarding our products and services, including our website: [www.camerabits.com](http://www.camerabits.com/) (the “ **Site** ”, and collectively, with our products and services, the “ **Services** ”). This Privacy Policy is in all respects subject to, our Terms of Use accessible at <http://www.camerabits.com/terms-of-use/>. Capitalized terms not defined on this page, have the meaning given to them in the Terms of Use.

 **Camera Bits is committed to protecting your privacy**. We will use the information that you provide to us as described below. Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, your personally identifiable information will never be rented, sold or otherwise provided to any third-party without your consent.

 **Certain information and/or personal information may be disclosed to third-parties in connection with and as necessitated by our normal provision of services, or in the ordinary course of your activity where there is no expectation of privacy**. By using our Site, by purchasing Camera Bits products or services, or by filing a Camera Bits Forum registration and providing your personally identifiable information, you confirm your acceptance of, and agree to be bound by, this Privacy Policy. **If you are not in agreement with this Privacy Policy, please do not use this Site, register as a member, or provide us any information.** By accepting this Privacy Policy, you expressly consent to our use of your personal information and its disclosure in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

 **Note on GDPR Compliance**

Camera Bits will adhere with the General Data Protection Regulation (the “ **GDPR** ”) adopted by the European Union. Namely, at any time, you may, subject to the applicable limitations of the GDPR:

  * request restriction or, or withdraw your consent regarding, the processing of your personal information.
  * request access to and rectification of your personal information.
  * request that your personal information be erased.
  * request details of the personal information we hold about you.

Any requests should be mailed, or called in, to us using the company information described at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

 **Information We Collect or Receive**. When you utilize the Services, we may collect certain information directly from you that you provide to us, as well as information that is automatically or passively collected from other sources, such as from your browser or device.

 **Information that you Provide**. The information that we may ask you to provide, or the information that you otherwise disclose, in connection with the Services may vary greatly, but is generally limited to names (or other identifier), email, and access credentials.

 **Forum**. Additionally, when you register for the Camera Bits Forums ([http://forums.camerabits.com](http://forums.camerabits.com/)), including the creation of your profile, and at other times during your membership, we will display some personal information on your profile, as dictated by you in the creation of your profile. Any information you choose to share should reflect how much you want others to know about you personally. Please consider carefully what information you wish to disclose and your desired level of anonymity.

 **Purchases**. When you make purchases on the Site, and at other times in your use of the Site, we make ask you to provide information which may personally identify you and/or allow us to contact you, such as your name and email address, user name and password, billing address, credit card number, applications purchased, date of purchase, and information about your computer and software.

 **Access Credentials**. When you sign into your account to use the Services, we use certain tracking technologies, such as cookies, to store your sign-in information.

 **Device, Usage, and Location Data**. When you access the Services, logs used to help us diagnose problems with our server, to administer the Site, and to otherwise provide our Services to you, may automatically collect standard web log entries for each page served, including your IP address, page URL, browser type, and language, access times, referring website addresses, information you search on the Site, date and timestamps associated with Site access and usage, system configuration information, metadata concerning the files that you upload/download, and other interactions with the Site and/or Services. Some of our products may store data locally on your computer (preferences, connection settings, image metadata). Our products contact our servers as part of the activation and deactivation processes, and information entered into the Registration dialog is logged on our licensing server, including computer identifying information and the IP address information. Checking for updates to our Services also sends computer identifying information and the information you entered into the Registration dialog.

 **Other Information**. Many electronic devices track real-time location-based information. Some files you share may be embedded with this location information. If you do not wish to share this information, do not upload those embedded files and/or turn off that feature on your camera, or other device.

 **How Camera Bits May Use or Disclose Information**

 **Operation of Services and our Business**. The personal information you provide, in combination with other information collected, will be used to operate the Site, to improve the quality of our Site, and to provide you with a better experience. Specifically, it may be used to: (i) provide you with important information about the product or service that you are using, including critical updates, notifications, and product announcements; (ii) diagnose problems with the Site; (iii) provide and improve functionality and user-friendliness of our Site; and (iv) better understand your needs and interests, and personalize and improve your experience. Additionally, In the event Camera Bits sells or transfers some or all of its assets, the information it collects may be disclosed to, and your personally identifiable information may be among those assets transferred.

 **Communications with you**. We may use your information for communications with you, such for as sending confirmation emails, authenticating your purchases, and for marketing of our Services to you. We distribute a newsletter via the email address you provide to us. If you no longer wish to receive this newsletter from us, you may “unsubscribe” by following the instructions in the email.

 **Security Compliance**. We use information to monitor and analyze use of the Services, to reduce fraud, software piracy, and protect our users and customers, and verify a user name and administer your use of the Services.

 **Legal Compliance**. Camera Bits may disclose information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process. Camera Bits may also disclose information to law enforcement officers or others, in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: enforce our Terms of Use; or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Camera Bits, its users or the general public.

 **Aggregated Information**. Camera Bits may disclose information in the form of aggregate data regarding user behavior, which do not identify any individual user.

 **Cookies and Tracking**

This Site also use “cookies” and other technologies to collect information, improve our Site, and provide the Services. Namely, we use these technologies to: (i) allow sign in and authentication of user accounts and to maintain preferences regarding your user experience; (ii) detect fraud, software piracy, and abuse of the Services; and (iii) gather usage and performance data. In addition, third parties may also be utilizing technologies when you use the Services.

 **Cookies**. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer or electronic device. We may use “persistent cookies” to save your user name and login password for future access to the Site. We may use “session ID cookies” to enable certain features of the Site, helping us to gain a better understanding of how you interact with the Site and Services, and to monitor aggregate web traffic routing on the Site and use of the Site and Services **.**

 **Locally stored objects and Web Beacons.** Locally stored objects are stored on your device or browser to provide Services that use Adobe Flash technology. Web beacons are small pieces of code used to collect data about users of the Services.

 **Your Preference Choices Regarding Disclosure and Communications.** Generally, your web browser is enabled to allow you the ability to manage cookies and other tracking technologies used by websites, including the ability to limit, manage, block and delete. The same may be utilized to manage the technologies’ collection of information and delivery to Camera Bits. However, note that blocking or limiting certain of the technologies may impair your ability to utilize or access certain features of the Site (such as keeping you signed in or remembering your preferences).

 **Third Party Websites**

This Privacy Policy applies to Camera Bits only. However, as we work with third parties in connection with the operation of the Services and our business, those third parties may collect or have access to your information necessary or appropriate for the function and operation of the Services and our business. Namely, Camera Bits works with the following Third Parties:

  *  **Website Presentation and Function**. The Site is built on and operates on the WordPress platform, a property of Automattic Inc. (<https://automattic.com/privacy>)
  *  **Payment Processing**. Purchases of Services are performed through PayPal.com, a property of PayPal Holdings, Inc. (<https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>), and Stripe.com, a property of Stripe, Inc. (<https://stripe.com/privacy>)
  *  **Service and Support**. Camera Bits utilizes Desk, a property of SalesForce.com, Inc. (<https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/>) to intake, respond to, and track customer support inquires. Additionally, Camera Bits utilizes TeamViewer, a property of TeamViewer GMBH (<https://www.teamviewer.us/privacy-policy>), to, with your permission and involvement, allow real time screen sharing access to assist in customer service and support.
  *  **General Business Operations**. Camera Bits utilizes Slack, a property of Slack Technologies, Inc. (https://slack.com/privacy-policy) for internal business purposes such as communicating between company departments and project collaboration.
  *  **Marketing**. Camera Bits utilizes Emma, a property of Emma, Inc. (https://myemma.com/legal/privacy-notice) for marketing of the Services such as our newsletters and for RSVPs to certain online marketing events, as well as, SurveyMonkey, a property of SurveyMonkey, Inc. (<https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/>) to survey information of our users for marketing, development, and other like purposes.

Additionally, Camera Bits may provide links to third party websites, which may have different privacy practices. We do not have any control over, the privacy policies of third-party websites, and encourage all users to read the privacy policies of each and every website visited.

 **Security and Limitations to Internet Privacy**

Camera Bits is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. However, there is no perfect security on the Internet. Despite the security measures we employ to protect your privacy, we cannot assure that your personal information, and other information that you provide or that we collect, will not be disclosed in contravention of this Privacy Policy. We consider the maintenance of your privacy most important. Nevertheless, given the possibility of the unlawful interception of information, we cannot promise and you should not expect that your information you provide to Camera Bits will always remain private or secure.

 **A Special Note About Minors and Children**

Persons under the age of majority in their applicable jurisdiction are not eligible to use our Site without the supervision of a parent or guardian. Camera Bits does not permit children under the age of 13 (or such lesser age as provided by the applicable jurisdiction) to use or access our site without supervisions of a parent of guardian. Camera Bits will not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 (or such lesser age as provided by the applicable jurisdiction). If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 (or such lesser age as provided by the applicable jurisdiction) has provided personal data to us without parental consent, please contact us as provided below.

Camera Bits strongly encourages all parents and guardians to:

  * Educate their children regarding information collection and usage.
  * Teach their children to provide personal information only with parental consent.
  * Monitor the online usage and behavior of their children.

 **Changes to Privacy Policy**

 **Please note this Privacy Policy may change from time to time**. We will post any changes to the Site, and we strongly encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy, most importantly, before you provide Camera Bits with any personal information. Your continued use of the Services after any changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the changes, please discontinue using the Services.

 **Inquiries**

If you have general inquiries about this Privacy Policy, this Site, or the Services, please contact Camera Bits via e-mail at privacy@camerabits.com or by regular mail to:

 **Attention: Privacy Manager  
** Camera Bits, Inc.  
471 S. 1st Ave.  
Hillsboro, OR 97123  
+1 503 547 2800
